<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Dan Denney - Super Social Front-End Dev</title>
 <link href="http://london-news.demo/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://london-news.demo"/>
 <updated>2013-03-21T23:14:50-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://dandenney.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Edward Hyde</name>
   <email>fake@mijingo.com</email>
 </author>

 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Playing With Data URIs</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-data-uris"/>
 		<updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-data-uris</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-data-uris/grossness.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Following up on
  &lt;a href='/posts/front-end-dev/going-live-with-number-five'&gt;my post yesterday,&lt;/a&gt;
  I thought I should quickly play with data URIs to see what they can do for performance. This is strictly sharing my learning and testing, not an explanation of how data URIs work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I have no idea what I'm doing.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I really don't have a grasp on this tech yet. I've read about them in lots of posts, but haven't really messed with them much. I mean, I understand that they are a way of writing the code for an asset directly into the HTML. How that works, how to troubleshoot or how to explain oddities are currently beyond my skillzzz.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Chris' recent post on
  &lt;a href='http://css-tricks.com/using-svg'&gt;using them with SVGS&lt;/a&gt;
  convinced me to try them out. Plus, Neil really digs them and actually
  &lt;a href='http://base64.neil.mixture.io'&gt;made an encoder.&lt;/a&gt;
  You know, for kicks while he was coding out a project.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I feel dirty and better at the same time.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Using them is kind of like drinking a natural vegetable shake. You know it's good for you, but it's icky and makes you shudder. The code that makes them is insane. Putting Sublime Text into full screen mode with my 1440x900 resolution, it takes 3-4 full swipes to scroll past the code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It is really easy, though. You drag your image into an encoder, copy, and paste the code into the src=&quot;&quot; of your image. Boom!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results (Home Page Only So Far)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm not 100% sure about the results. What I can see is that the page weight went down (very surprisingly, but thanks to gzip). The page load time went down, but the requests stayed the same. This was a little bit of a WTF moment for me. I'll spend a little more time trying to dig up an answer because I was expecting it to be reduced by the 10 SVGs that are now data URIs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Page Weight&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;linked SVG&lt;/small&gt;
  229 KB vs. 185 KB
  &lt;small&gt;data URI&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;HTTP Requests:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;linked SVG&lt;/small&gt;
  20 vs. 20
  &lt;small&gt;data URI&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Page Load Time:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;linked SVG&lt;/small&gt;
  1.67 seconds vs. 1.29 seconds
  &lt;small&gt;data URI&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Going Live With Number Five</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/going-live-with-number-five"/>
 		<updated>2013-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/going-live-with-number-five</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/going-live-with-number-five/stage.png' /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Month (or so) Late&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have been planning to write this since before I launched this year's
  &lt;a href='http://frontendconf.com'&gt;Front-End Design Conference&lt;/a&gt;
  site. Instead of timing it with the launch of the site, I'm piggybacking on the launch of the app that I used to build it:
  &lt;a href='http://mixture.io'&gt;Mixture.io&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I got lucky and scored a copy of the alpha for the app and have been chatting and learning from
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/neiltak'&gt;Neil Kinnish&lt;/a&gt;
  as they have been building it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Goals for this year's site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I really dug the look of the '12 version, but felt pretty horrible about the markup and the performance. It was done in a rush and those things suffered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For the '13 version I wanted to significantly reduce the HTTP requests, make better use of preprocessors, reduce page weight, reduce the amount of text and move away from Rails.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;From Prototype to Production&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I began using Mixture to prototype mainly for the ability to use some includes and fake some data (attendee profiles). I quickly learned that all of the front-end best practices were baked into the app: CSS minification, JS concatenation and minification, image optimization, S3 asset hosting and gzipping to mention a few.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Luckily, Neil offered to let me test using their pro option to host the site and I was no longer building a prototype!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have some loose ends and can do some more optimization, but here is how the new version is stacking up. Keep in mind I haven't had to even think about minifiying, S3, etc. It was all done for me with Mixture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Home Visual Comparison:
  &lt;a href='http://frontenddesignconf.heroku.com'&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;
  vs.
  &lt;a href='http://frontenddesignconference.com'&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one major change that is kind of cheating the comparison. I realized it was pretty irresponsible to automatically load all of the attendee profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Home Page Weight&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  1.8 MB vs. 229 KB
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Home HTTP Requests:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  261 vs. 20
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Home Page Load Time:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  13.83 seconds vs. 1.67 seconds
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Prior Year Visual Comparison:
  &lt;a href='http://frontenddesignconf.heroku.com/2011'&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;
  vs.
  &lt;a href='http://frontenddesignconference.com/2011'&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page is actually a little heavier but that is because I added in 9 sponsor logos. Overall, I'm still happy with the improvement in reducing the requests and load time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prior Year (2011) Page Weight&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  625 KB vs. 641 KB
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prior Year (2011) HTTP Requests:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  54 vs. 39
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prior Year (2011) Page Load Time:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;2012&lt;/small&gt;
  6.47 seconds vs. 2.28 seconds
  &lt;small&gt;2013&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wanna play?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's hard to explain how rad Mixture is without a video. If you want to play,
  &lt;a href='http://mixture.io'&gt;download Mixture&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href='https://github.com/dandenney/front-end-conf'&gt;grab the front-end-conf repo.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  p + h3 { margin-top: 2em; }
&lt;/style&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Ricardo Rally Time</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/general/ricardo-rally-time"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/general/ricardo-rally-time</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/posts/general/ricardo-rally-time/all2.png' /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help Me, Help Ricardo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ricardo Gimenes, who does all of the illustrations for Front-End Conf, is crowd funding an iPad app.
  &lt;a href='http://catarse.me/en/vectorlooza'&gt;Vectorlooza&lt;/a&gt;
  is his take on how an illustrator app on the iPad should look and feel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The video is entertaining and it looks like it would be a rad app. I'm a huge Ricardo fanboy, so I want to try to help with the last push for him to make his goal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You know you want a character...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I backed the project at a level that will reward me with 3 characters (if the project reaches its goal). I will gladly give these characters away in exchange for some social sharing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Tweet something to promote Vectorlooza, link up
  &lt;a href='http://catarse.me/en/vectorlooza'&gt;http://catarse.me/en/vectorlooza&lt;/a&gt;
  and include #frontendconf so I can track them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If the project reaches its goal, I will do a random draw from those who share for the characters.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Sass Color Variable Pop Quiz</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/sass-color-variable-pop-quiz"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/sass-color-variable-pop-quiz</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;I had a question about color variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Each project has some really easy to define colors that can get you started. Base font color, a highlight color, link color, etc. Once you're a few hundred lines in though, you start coming across more colors that are used for shading, borders, highlights, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I knew
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/nickawalsh'&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/drewbarontini'&gt;Drew&lt;/a&gt;
  would have answers, so I popped some questions into the Envy Design Campfire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  How many times do you have to use a color before it should be a variable and how do you conjure up names beyond the first 6 or 7?
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Nick chimed in with &quot;if I use it more than three-ish times, it's usually time to variableize it or if it's a completely different color that doesn't fall into a sass-adjustment case (e.g blue theme, random green button appears)&quot;. Drew followed up with a gist of examples that was something like this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;&lt;!-- / ----- Variables ----- // --&gt;
&lt;!-- / Brand Colors --&gt;
$color-brand-a: #606E67
$color-brand-b: #C98344
&lt;!-- / Base Colors --&gt;
$color-base: #636365
$color-body: #EFEDDF
$color-border: #A9A9A9
$color-header: #3F4944
$color-input: #DCD7CE
&lt;!-- / Button Colors --&gt;
$color-btn-a: #228B9B
$color-btn-b: #783737
$color-btn-c: #BFBEB2
&lt;!-- / Utility Colors --&gt;
$color-error: $color-btn-b
$color-success: $color-header
&lt;!-- / Container Colors --&gt;
$color-block-a: $color-header
$color-block-b: desaturate(darken($color-body, 4%), 11%)
$color-block-c: #D4D5C2
$color-card-a: lighten($color-body, 4%)
$color-card-b: $color-block-b&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To the Twitters!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I thought that this might be something cool that other people would have an opinion on. So I tweeted the questions and I'm sharing the answers below. Please chime in if you have a method. I love learning how other people approach these types of things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;
    Daniel Peplow aka
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/danielpeplow'&gt;@danielpeplow&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    How many times before variableizing?
    &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Naming approach?
    &lt;b&gt;red1, red2, darkred1, darkred2, primarybrand, secondarybrand depending on what is required&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;
    Chris Brauckmuller aka
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/cbrauckmuller'&gt;@cbrauckmuller&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    How many times before variableizing?
    &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Naming approach?
    &lt;b&gt;
      It depends. For neutrals I usually have $gray, $gray-light and $gray-dark. For the main brand colors, I would name the original color something like $brand-green. Then if I needed variants of that, I might do $brand-green-lighterX, where X just represents how many percent lighter it is versus the original.
    &lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Sample?
    &lt;a href='https://github.com/cbrauckmuller/helium/blob/master/scss/config.scss'&gt;https://github.com/cbrauckmuller/helium/blob/master/scss/config.scss&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;
    Elyse Holladay aka
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/elyseholladay'&gt;@elyseholladay&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    How many times before variableizing?
    &lt;b&gt;3&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Naming approach?
    &lt;b&gt;
      In a small/personal project, sometimes I'll just say 'blue' 'darkblue', etc.
      In the large apps I work on, especially ones that require theming, I try to cut down on # of available colors by using darken/lighten in SASS rather than 2 different shades of blue. I name &quot;global&quot; colors like black/white by their names. For themable colors, I go primary/secondary/tertiary/highlight/error/success, and so on.
    &lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Sample?
    &lt;a href='https://gist.github.com/4550373'&gt;https://gist.github.com/4550373&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;
    Chase Woodford aka
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/chase1263070'&gt;@chase1263070&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    How many times before variableizing?
    &lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Naming approach?
    &lt;b&gt;
      I try to stick to a ${groupName}-{differentiator} naming convention.
    &lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    Sample?
    &lt;a href='https://github.com/chasewoodford/chasewoodford.com/blob/master/css/sass/_variables.scss'&gt;https://github.com/chasewoodford/chasewoodford.com/blob/master/css/sass/_variables.scss&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Tech Conference Diversity</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/tech-conference-diversity"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/tech-conference-diversity</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The lack of gender diversity in tech conferences hit the tipping point last week. Another all-male lineup was announced and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing the speaker count being so high added the extra frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, we have gotten &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.iawriter.com/help/kb/general-questions/markdown-syntax-reference-guide&quot;&gt;real pledges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://conferencequotas.com&quot;&gt;awful satire pledges&lt;/a&gt; and countless Twitter arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could benefit from more diversity in our conference lineups, but the solution isn&amp;rsquo;t any form of affirmative action. We need the people that organize conferences to be considerate and to make an effort to discover new people that would love to share their knowledge and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can speak from experience on this one and they are very easy to find.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Cherry Picking from Frameworks</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/bootstrap-customization-ftw"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/bootstrap-customization-ftw</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If there is such a thing as front-end framework camps, I have been carrying the &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; flag for a while. As a full framework, I prefer it over &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. I prefer the code style and the use of Sass instead of Less, primarily. I also like that there&amp;rsquo;s less in it and it is more tightly bundled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my team and I don&amp;rsquo;t use a framework for projects. So when I&amp;rsquo;m looking at their docs, it&amp;rsquo;s to determine some best practices for specific modules. This is where Bootstrap excels. Their documentation and their code lends itself to cherry picking more easily than Foundation does. The fact that you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/customize.html&quot;&gt;customize your Bootstrap download&lt;/a&gt; sealed the deal on it being the better resource for cherry picking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I think it&amp;rsquo;s great that they are going different directions. Bootstrap seems to be moving towards being a collection of small systems and Foundation is focused on being a single system. It will keep them both growing instead of duplicating and competing, which rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Production-Shipping Balance</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/production-consumption-balance"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/production-consumption-balance</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some people struggle with a work/life balance. You&amp;rsquo;ll see tons of articles on how people try to keep it in check. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky in that I have a wonderful wife and family that come up with plenty of things for me to do besides work. If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for them, I would probably &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo; way too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I have been really struggling lately is in the production/consumption balance. For the past 5 years or so, I have spent a large amount of my non-billable time consuming information about  web design and dev. I&amp;rsquo;m insatiable when it comes to learning about the web. Recently I realized that spending so much time consuming has left me with much less time for producing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, I have probably consumed 10+ things per day. This being some combination of reading articles, checking out sites and watching videos. My read-it-later queue is generally over 100 items at a time. I&amp;rsquo;m significantly slowing down. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been more in the 1-5 range per day and I&amp;rsquo;m using that time to produce things: mainly writing and working on a backbone project. My focus now is much heavier on learning by doing instead of learning by reading. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where it takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Subtly Seeking Svbtle</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/subtly-seeking-svbtle"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/subtly-seeking-svbtle</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://svbtle.com&quot;&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt; worthy. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I would ever actually apply, but I want to get better at writing timely, opinion pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I begin my not-so-subtle pursuit of Svbtle-quality writing. I aim to write more and write more better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>re:build Conference 2012</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;div class='container'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I was recently lucky enough to tag along with
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/jasonvanlue'&gt;Jason VanLue&lt;/a&gt;
    up to Indianapolis to attend
    &lt;a href='http://rebuildconf.com'&gt;re:build 2012.&lt;/a&gt;
    Big, big thank you to Jason for working it out,
    &lt;a href='http://envylabs.com'&gt;Envy Labs&lt;/a&gt;
    for sending me and to the re:build team for their hospitality.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Indy&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Prior to heading up, I really didn't know much about Indianapolis or the web community in the area. The city is absolutely charming and the people are warm and friendly. The architecture is gorgeous, there is a bustling downtown and they have a penchant for craft beer (which is near and dear to my heart and belly).
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/slogan.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Before leaving, Jason and I roamed around downtown for a bit and I took this pic from a monument. I knew I'd be writing up my thoughts on the conf and that the words etched into stone here seem to be amongst the Indy core values and are definitely a part of re:build.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Overall Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The event is coordinated by
    &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/jlharter'&gt;Justin Harter&lt;/a&gt;
    and
    &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/tonydewan'&gt;Tony Dewan.&lt;/a&gt;
    They absolutely know how to make everyone feel special. Their attention to detail, clear communication and calm demeanors set the tone for the whole event. I was extra lucky in that I was an attendee but I also got to see how they took care of the speakers. They are fantastic hosts on both sides so I highly recommend attending and accepting speaking invitations from them.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Pre-Party&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I attend (and Twitter stalk) many conferences. A popular 'problem' is that people arrive to the area the night before the event and want to meet up with people. You'll often see pockets of tweets with hashtags looking for other attendees. Understanding this, the re:build team put together a pre-party at this awesome place called
    &lt;a href='http://www.speakeasyindy.com'&gt;The Speakeasy.&lt;/a&gt;
    It is a local hub with a startup focus that has a wonderful industrial design. Conversations were helped along by some local microbrew, thanks to
    &lt;a href='http://www.exacttarget.com'&gt;ExactTarget&lt;/a&gt;
    sponsoring the evening (and the speaker dinner). From what I saw, people took it pretty easy so they were still ready for some inspiration and learning the next day.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Registration&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Getting a couple hundred people checked in can be tricky but having registration available at the pre-party helped reduce the crowd in the morning. They also had a big room filled with coffee, snacks and tall tables for people to eat and converse around. Thank you very much to
    &lt;a href='http://getharvest.com'&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt;
    for sponsoring the goodies.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;img alt='Harvest Sponsored Area' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/harvest-room.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Location&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Character and attention to detail were present in everything, but the location was the 'biggest' example of it. The presentations were done in the gymnasium of a community center which hosts local artists. It also is an active gym for the church (which I believe is a school) next-door. There were so many natural aesthetic plusses and the team made sure that it also was a great place for A/V.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    As you roamed the halls, they were filled with the work of local artists and you could actually see and hear people working in their studios. The architecture was fantastic and the gym felt like we were in the movie
    &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091217'&gt;Hoosiers.&lt;/a&gt;
    They rigged the place with a large amount of tech, with a giant screen on each side of the stage and numerous video cameras. Sound quality and visibility were excellent no matter where you were. I believe they will be releasing the videos later on so keep an eye out for updates.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Food and Drinks&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Coffee was available all day, which is my ultimate test of a good conference. I'm mostly kidding, but as a coffee junkie it is really appreciated. They had a good mix of healthy and yummy snacks available all day and they also provided lunch via food trucks. Big thank you to
    &lt;a href='http://www.smallboxweb.com'&gt;SmallBox&lt;/a&gt;
    for sponsoring lunch!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I happened to pick the busiest (and possibly slowest) of the 3 trucks, so it took the full hour-and-a-half to get through the line. Having the choice and providing the trucks was really awesome, though. It was one less thing to think about and I was able to have a really awesome conversation with
    &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/robertHarr'&gt;Rob&lt;/a&gt;
    and
    &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/jeremyloyd'&gt;Jeremy&lt;/a&gt;
    from
    &lt;a href='http://sparkbox.com'&gt;Sparkbox&lt;/a&gt;
    while waiting in line.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The After-Party&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The after-party was back at The Speakeasy and started right after the event, which is awesome. Some people like to go chat for a bit and then leave while others like to eat and then hit the party. Starting right away always accommodates both. Big thank you to
    &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;
    for sponsoring the party!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Part of The Speakeasy building is a place called Developer Town, which I had to take a pic of for you to believe. It is a big space where developers rent out little sheds inside to work in.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;img alt='Developer Town' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/developer-town.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    On top of setting up a great environment and personal feel, the re:build guys stacked up a diverse lineup of speakers and presentations. Topics covered the range of industry topics from working environments to design samples, UX and code implementations. Here are some tidbits and takeaways from each one.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    You can check out their full bios, plus Twitter and website links on the
    &lt;a href='http://www.rebuildconf.com#speakers'&gt;re:build site.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
    I thought I should use a little hover love in them since Jenn's talk was so much fun.
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Zach Holman&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Zach Holman at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-zach-holman.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Zach hails from
    &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;
    and he shared many of the things that go into putting together a great team of creatives. He gave examples of how to create a culture that you want and how to deal with the &quot;internet dicks&quot; that spring up as you release things. You can check out the slides and audio already on
    &lt;a href='https://speakerdeck.com/u/holman/p/the-product-is-the-byproduct'&gt;Speaker Deck.&lt;/a&gt;
    My favorite piece was that you want fixers on your team, so hire those that are &quot;bothered by suck&quot;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;David Kadavy&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='David Kadavy at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-david-kadavy.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    David is the author of
    &lt;a href=''&gt;Design for Developers&lt;/a&gt;
    and his talk focused on an intro to some UX principles, namely use cases and user personas. He used some good examples of the difference in experiences between Craigslist vs. Airbnb, typical weather app experiences vs. the Dark Cloud app and typical online clothiers vs. Gilt. He also gave a quick sample of applying some possible user personas to how the Twitter iPad app was designed. He had a relaxed, conversational style and is quite funny off the stage.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Jason VanLue&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Jason VanLue at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-jason-vanlue.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I hadn't heard of this guy before so I was curious what he'd bring to the table. I kid, I kid. I work with Jason at
    &lt;a href='http://envylabs.com'&gt;Envy Labs,&lt;/a&gt;
    where he is the Hovering Director of Art. Jason is a great speaker and I really enjoy his take on design as a way to solve problems. There are lots of great takeaways throughout his talk, but the main theme is that screens could be as life changing as the automobile was for humankind. We should be focusing on problems that we want to solve for people and on designing for the other side of the screen. The history in his talk is fantastic and it is great to get so much inspiration from people outside of our industry.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Willo O'Brien&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Willo O'Brien at re:build&quot; src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-willo-obrien.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Willo has a great story of how she has gone from creating clothing to co-founding and consulting for startups for creatives. Her presentation was primarily about figuring out &quot;how you work best&quot;. She highly recommends making time for serendipity and to manage energy, not time. For her, this has been a matter of taking breaks that she calls art dates and establishing personal relationships with the people that she works with. A few resources that she recommends are:
    &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/StrengthsFinder-2-0-Tom-Rath/dp/159562015X'&gt;Book: Strengths Finder,&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href='https://s3.amazonaws.com/skillshare/assets/hybrid/project-briefs/MEValuesExercise.pdf'&gt;Me Values Exercise&lt;/a&gt;
    and the
    &lt;a href='https://www.superbetter.com/'&gt;Super Better App.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Patrick Filler&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Patrick Filler at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-patrick-filler.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Patrick is a front-end dev at
    &lt;a href='http://www.getharvest.com'&gt;Harvest,&lt;/a&gt;
    where he was part of the development of the
    &lt;a href='http://harvesthq.github.com/chosen'&gt;Chosen JavaScript Plugin.&lt;/a&gt;
    He shared how they had originally made it for Harvest in order to improve their forms and the decision to open source it. The best part of open sourcing projects is that anyone can do it. There are no connections necessary, it is a meritocracy. Put yourself out there and release some things that you're working on or volunteer your skills to help out projects that you're interested in!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;David Sleight&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='David Sleight at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-david-sleight.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    David is the product lead at
    &lt;a href='http://readability.com'&gt;Readability&lt;/a&gt;
    and he shared how publishing has been evolving via technology. Basically, there is a bigger demand for content in the world than in any time in history. The audience is huge, but diffuse. He shared that the keys items that differentiate good resources are APIs, content planning and flexible design. Also, he shared how natural language processing is impacting the future of content. Here are some recommended reads from his presentation:
    &lt;a href='http://www.alistapart.com/articles/orbital-content'&gt;Orbital Content,&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href='http://contentsmagazine.com'&gt;Contents Magazine,&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href='http://qz.com'&gt;Quartz,&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href='http://evening-edition.com'&gt;The Evening Edition,&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href='http://www.thesilenthistory.com'&gt;The Silent History,&lt;/a&gt;
    and
    &lt;a href='https://www.atavist.com/stories'&gt;The Atavist.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Jenn Lukas&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Jenn Lukas at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-jenn-lukas.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Jenn is a front-end dev at Happy Cog and I was especially looking forward to seeing her present. (I hope to see her speak at this cool event in Florida sometime.) She shared many ways to surprise and delight your users with hover-based interactions. She shared many great examples of hovers in action and then followed that up with how to use the dev tools to learn how they were achieved. Each example also came with code samples so her slides will be really helpful. One quote that I can't leave out is &quot;Color fade is the smooth jazz of hovers&quot;. She shared a cool way of animating height by using max-height: 0 and encouraged everyone to check out
    &lt;a href='http://css-tricks.com/almanac/properties/b/backface-visibility'&gt;backface-visibility.&lt;/a&gt;
    Her excitement for these things was infectious and there were lots of cats!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Mark Otto&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Mark Otto at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-mark-otto.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Mark is one of the creators of
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap'&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;
    and has recently left Twitter and joined Github. He shared how important it is to design how stuff works and the 5 principles behind creating Bootstrap. They were: treat the docs like they're the product, say no all the time, educate by enforcing coding styles, help folks avoid writing JavaScript and reach every person on the planet. Everything is a design system and theirs consisted of base classes, prefix modifiers, formatting, property order and compiling. Going forward, his main goal is to help awesome poeple do awesome stuff.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='block-speaker'&gt;
  &lt;div class='rebuild-speaker'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Dave Shea&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Dave Shea at re:build' src='/images/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012/speaker-dave-shea.jpg' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Dave is O.G. when it comes to the design and dev community. He wrapped up the conference with a walk through how we got to where we are today. Part of this is his work with
    &lt;a href='http://www.csszengarden.com'&gt;CSS Zen Garden,&lt;/a&gt;
    which really helped push CSS layout. One of the more interesting things was about how the original purpose behind the web was to create structure for CERN information. Early users of the web showed pretty quickly that we were more interested in visuals than order. CSS Zen Garden was created to help display what could be done visually with CSS. It had an agenda, a place and a time.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I had a really great time and it was awesome to also get to meet some people that use
      &lt;a href='http://codeschool.com'&gt;Code School.&lt;/a&gt;
      I really love to learn about the people that use it and what types of positions that they have. Thank you specifically to
      &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/mtheoryx'&gt;David Poindexter&lt;/a&gt;
      and
      &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/samkligerman'&gt;Sam Kligerman&lt;/a&gt;
      for sharing their stories.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div class='post-standard-signature'&gt;
      &lt;small&gt;September 22, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id='disqus_thread'&gt;
      &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
      var disqus_shortname = 'dandenney';
      (function() {
      var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
      dsq.src = 'http://' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
      (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
      })();
      &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com&quot; class=&quot;dsq-brlink&quot;&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class=&quot;logo-disqus&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;link href='/stylesheets/posts/conferences/rebuild-conference-2012.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Future of Front-End Conf</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/future-of-front-end-conf"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/future-of-front-end-conf</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/posts/conferences/future-of-front-end-conf/front-end-2009.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Future of Front-End Conf&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get to the future, I'll share a tidbit about the past. When I first got Cherrie's approval for doing the 2009 event, I wasn't thinking about 5 years down the road. I wasn't even thinking beyond the day of the first event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumping out there and just doing it was one of the best decisions I've made. However, trying to just do something cool without a plan leads to some issues. The result of this has been that every year after the event we talk about how it went and then decide if we can do it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going into our fifth year, I don't want to have that conversation afterwards. The last event was by far my favorite. Hanging out with people beforehand, the fantastic presentations of the day, dressing up in goofy stuff for the photo booth, air guitar on a chair during karaoke, the day 2 speakers and the conversations Saturday night absolutely rocked. The awesome sponsors made the amenities great and the whole thing went wonderfully. In our final review, we knew that we want to run this event for as long as people are interested in coming. I love what the conference has become and (in considering future events) my number one goal is not to break it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='center-content'&gt;
  &lt;img src='/images/posts/conferences/future-of-front-end-conf/front-end-conftocat.svg' /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scaling, Sponsors and Budget&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we've grown into an event that has sold out at 200 and 250 available registrations, the first question is &quot;do we continue growing?&quot; Considering my goal of 'not breaking it', I don't plan to raise the number of available spots, at least for 2013. With all of the registrations, speakers, sponsors and our awesome team it ends up close to 300 people. That size felt really right, so we're going to tweak how we handle the student tickets but keep things at the same 300 people level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awesome companies that have sponsored the conference have absolutely carried us through. If it weren't for the sponsors in the first 2 years, we wouldn't have been able to continue. Luckily, we learned a few things in those 2 and tweaked sponsorship funds to go to the fun extras like t-shirts, notepads, chocolate covered bacon and free after party drinks. The level of all these things felt great in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of those two combine into the &quot;big one&quot;: the budget. The first couple of years ran in the red, but each of the second two were able to stay in the black. Overall, it's still red but the black trend is enough to keep going on. Everything about 2012 felt right and we want to be able to deliver that level of experience every year. There's always room for more extras, but we wouldn't want to take things away. The problem is that without the sponsors, it would have been in the red. So, we're going to adjust the pricing this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Price Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure that we have enough to cover the expenses, we need to raise the price by approximately $30 per person for half of the attendees. This made for an interesting decision: do we keep the early bird at $119 and raise the main price to $179 or just bring the early bird up to $149? Always trying to be as fair as possible, I would prefer for everyone to have the same cost than a $60 difference. Plus the early bird is usually 100 vs. 150, so it's raising the price on less people. We're going to make it one flat rate of $149.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only discount that we will have is that we will offer up to 25 spots as student tickets at our usual $99. In the past, we have done this just for Full Sail students, but we have found more interested people. This year we will open it up to the first 25 students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will ensure that we can run the event at the same level as 2012. Of course, we will look for sponsors that want to make the day even better. Cherrie always has great ideas for making things special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A less important fix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src='/images/posts/conferences/future-of-front-end-conf/front-end-logo.png' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The logo has plagued me since 2009. As part of not thinking beyond the day of the first event, I made the &quot;logo&quot; to match the site. The original site (which I scared myself by looking at a few weeks ago) was normal on the left and used sketches and sketched type on the right. It was supposed to look unfinished as it technically was. It changed as things changed in the few months while we planned that first event. People have asked me many times about why the sketched part begins at the 't'. I don't have a good answer, it was just closer to being half. Either way, it's going away.
  &lt;a href='http://ricardogimenes.com'&gt;Ricardo Gimenes'&lt;/a&gt;
  work with the characters is the true branding, so I'm just going to start using a web font to make the Front-End a solid red. Whew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Excited for 2013&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some ideas for 2013. First off, I'm going to to get the topics in a timely manner. Speakers and topics will be available when the site launches, which will be early '13. Luckily, I had lightly discussed speaking with a full lineup before 2012 even ran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm also going to
  &lt;a href='http://css-tricks.com/lodge'&gt;completely rip off Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt;
  and screencast the realign. I'm pretty happy with the overall look of the site, but not the performance. I'll be converting the site to Haml, Sass and Compass, improving the small screen experience and making design decisions along the way. I'm certainly no Mr. Coyier in either skill or charisma, but I think it will be fun to share the techniques in building the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're also going to have an optional workshop on the Thursday before the big day. I have wanted to run one for the last couple of years, but finally found the right fit to make it work. More on that later…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is totally not official, but we are looking at June 21st and 22nd for 2013. Boom!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>I'm an Aethestics Snob</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/im-an-aethestics-snob"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/im-an-aethestics-snob</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s why I paid for &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinboard.in&quot;&gt;pinboard&lt;/a&gt; but then left it for &lt;a href=&quot;http://kippt.com&quot;&gt;Kippt&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s how I judge any service that I&amp;rsquo;m checking out and especially how I read information online. There are probably less than 5 sites that I actually read straight from the site. The rest go to Readability to either read now or saved to read later. Tapbots integrating that into their Twitter app was amazing for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is huge for people that spend lots of time in front of screens. The minimum requirement is usability but aesthetics are used for driving enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Redesign Day</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/redesign-day"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/redesign-day</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One small step for the web, one giant leap for responsive web design. I&amp;rsquo;m being dramatic, but yesterday was a big day for #RWD and the web in general. It was redesign launch day, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://elementcreative.com&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://paravelinc.com&quot;&gt;Paravel&lt;/a&gt; both showing off their latest versions of their sites. As cool as they are, two web shops releasing responsive redesigns isn&amp;rsquo;t that big of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://disney.com&quot;&gt;Disney&lt;/a&gt; kind of are, though. Microsoft released only a home page redesign, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great step in the right direction. Disney went further than the home page but still has plenty of content linked that isn&amp;rsquo;t responsive…yet. The reason that I see this as important is that they are introducing it to their markets and leading them by doing it. This will be huge for enterprise and entertainment sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress introduced responsive to publishers with their free 2011 theme. This enabled publishers to begin producing content that could then be consumed more easily across a wide range of devices. The Boston Globe lead the charge into news/media delivery and now we will see the demand surge in business and entertainment. With a much wider array of content, there will be fantastic solutions that come out of the teams behind these projects. It is going to be an exciting couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Jared Erondu</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/jared-erondu"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/jared-erondu</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I listened to 2 different interviews with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jarederondu.com&quot;&gt;Jared Erondu&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://younggunsshow.com&quot;&gt;Young Guns Show&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://theeastwing.net&quot;&gt;The East Wing&lt;/a&gt; did a great job of both doing interviews with him and getting out different stories and topics. He&amp;rsquo;s a pretty awesome dude and definitely someone to keep an eye on in &lt;a href=&quot;http://theindustry.cc&quot;&gt;&amp;lsquo;the industry&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Ideas</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/ideas"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/ideas</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have too many ideas. I&amp;rsquo;m certainly not alone, it&amp;rsquo;s an effect of being a part of this amazing time for the web. The problem is that having so many ideas and not executing is like carrying baggage. When I see things get released that are close to ideas that I have it is both frustrating and rewarding. I get frustrated that I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it, but pleased that people that I consider much smarter than I am saw similar opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have been working on lately is allowing myself to think through something, play with the idea for a bit and then decide if I&amp;rsquo;m really going to do it or not. If I&amp;rsquo;m not going to start doing it this week, I&amp;rsquo;m writing it off. Execution is the only thing that matters and if I won&amp;rsquo;t set aside the time to execute on them they don&amp;rsquo;t matter. It&amp;rsquo;s hard though, as I&amp;rsquo;m trying to narrow down what to do of my 4 longest living ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>I'm Down With SVG</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;article class='post'&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;I'm Down with SVG... Yeah You Know Me&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      After coming across a couple of articles
      &lt;a href='http://samsoff.es/posts/wrangling-svgs'&gt;Wrangling SVGs&lt;/a&gt;
      and
      &lt;a href='http://dcurt.is/pixel-fitting'&gt;Pixel Fitting&lt;/a&gt;
      , I wanted to check out what SVG can do. While many people are using them for icons and logos, I was particularly interested in how they can render
      &lt;a href='http://ricardogimenes.com'&gt;Ricardo Gimenes'&lt;/a&gt;
      awesome illustrations for the
      &lt;a href='http://frontendconf.com'&gt;Front-End Conf site.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The crazy cool part about SVG is that you can just save one out from Illustrator and put it into an image tag. Of course, not for IE8 and lower but that's luckily not a concern. (There are polyfills for them for those, though.) Let's get right into comparing a transparent png and an svg of a character. I chose the one for
      &lt;a href='http://www.gdifeterici.com/'&gt;Gio Difeterici&lt;/a&gt;
      because it has a good level of detail and it's just so cool.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Original size from the site&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;div class='columns-two'&gt;
      &lt;div class='column'&gt;
        &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as a png' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.png' /&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;small&gt;Transparent .png, 401px x 466px, 21kb&lt;/small&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class='column'&gt;
        &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as svg' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.svg' /&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;small&gt;SVG, 401px x 466px, 15kb&lt;/small&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I'm using a retina MBP, so at regular size I can see the png start to lose detail. On the other hand, the svg is shimmering like Ricardo just finished making it in Illustrator. It looks amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Resizing with CSS to 50%&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;div class='columns-two small-screen'&gt;
      &lt;div class='column'&gt;
        &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as a png' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.png' /&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;small&gt;Transparent .png, 200px x 232px, 21kb&lt;/small&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class='column'&gt;
        &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as svg' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.svg' /&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;small&gt;SVG, 200px x 232px, 15kb&lt;/small&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This would represent shrinking an image down for the pixel density. They both look really good and each have minor issues. The png gets a little blurry in the top of the hair and the svg has some sharp pixel issues on the tip of the paintbrush. Of the two, I'd still pick the svg. It is slightly more sharp and 6kb smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Flexible width set to fill 100% of the container&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='columns-two large-screen'&gt;
    &lt;div class='column'&gt;
      &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as a png' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.png' /&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;small&gt;Transparent .png, Set to 100% width, 21kb&lt;/small&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class='column'&gt;
      &lt;img alt='Gio DiFeterici character as svg' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg/gio-difeterici.svg' /&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;small&gt;SVG, Set to 100% width, 15kb&lt;/small&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is where the magic happens. The clarity is fantastic scaling up. There are some slight pixel issues around the tip of the paint brush, which is why Sam Soffes recommends making the svg the actual intended size. The cool part is that even with doing a small and large version, there will only be 2 versions instead of doing 2 small and 2 large ones to include the retina screens.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;I'll be using SVG for the realign&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Based on what I have seen here, I will be converting all of the characters to svg for the realign. I would love to have a good solution for a red curtain background that I use as it is one of the biggest hits for file size. If I find a good solution for that, I will definitely share.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;September 30, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list-inline list-actions&quot;&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;link href='/stylesheets/posts/front-end-dev/im-down-with-svg.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Startups</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/startups"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/startups</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read a fantastic post by Paul Graham tonight, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/growth.html&quot;&gt;Startup = Growth&lt;/a&gt; in which he systematically ripped apart my thoughts on startups. If there is someone who can define what startups are about, it is Paul Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have misjudged many companies as startups and have been a little indignant about the whole model of &amp;ldquo;eyeballs are greater than revenue&amp;rdquo;. A lot of what he says makes sense and it has put me in the right frame of mind for understanding them. It was long, but fantastic and I highly recommend reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Circles Conf 2012</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/circles-conf-2012"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/conferences/circles-conf-2012</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;article class='post'&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Circles Conference 2012&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I am flying back home from Dallas, where Cherrie and I attended the first
      &lt;a href='http://www.circlesconference.com'&gt;Circles Conference.&lt;/a&gt;
      If you haven't heard of it before, it was an event to bring together creatives that do work for non-profit and/or religious organizations. Ismael Burciaga, aka Ish, had the idea for the event which is why we had to be there.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you haven't met Ish, he is awesome. We met him when he came to Front-End Conf in 2011 and he was everywhere throughout the weekend helping to make things fun. He's one of those people with the creative gift and is super friendly and energetic. As soon as he said he was doing an event, we knew we were going.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To save you the long description and breakdown, the event was really good. If you are familiar with Ish's work, you know that he consistently delivers high quality designs. The event reflected that in all aspects: location, organization, supplies and speaker choices. If you are looking for an inspirational event, keep your eyes out for future Circles Confs.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As far as my personal takeaway, I go to events for three reasons in this order: to meet people who work in our industry, to learn from my peers and to learn how other events run. Circles had lots of time for meeting people. It was never too much time, meaning that it didn't feel delayed but more importantly it didn't feel rushed. I met some wonderful people, heard great stories of people's paths on the stage and took home some tips for running my events.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Day One&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We took a cab into 'downtown' Grapevine, which has a lot of character. Main street has been preserved to still have that 'old west' feel. Brick buildings line a long straight street and there are items from American history all around: a log cabin, a funeral carriage, old oil pumps and gas pumps, etc. It made me feel like I should be rocking a hip holster with a six-shooter as I walked around.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;The Theater&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The actual theater itself was gorgeous. Registration was set up in a very smart way to keep people moving through some thin hallways. Pick up your badge in one area, move off to the t-shirts and then turn the corner to the swag. The t-shirts packaging was the coolest way that I have seen shirts given away at an event. Each shirt was in a box which looked like a small pizza box and featured the handiwork of Kyle Steed.) Thank you to
      &lt;a href='http://www.printedthreads.com'&gt;Printed Threads&lt;/a&gt;
      for sponsoring them.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I'm going to share the general idea behind the presentation, a few details and my takeaways from them. Of course, everyone gets different things from presentations, so these are just my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;ul class='circles-talks'&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Kyle Steed' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/kyle_steed.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kyle Steed&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Kyle shared the story of his path from leaving a job in order to pursue his passion and do work that he believes in. To help others do the same, he shared thoughts with a common goal: Focus on simplicity, being present and what is most important to you. We got to learn what things are important to him, how he focuses on simplicity in his work and how he takes steps in his life to 'be more than what he does'.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Kyle has a very chill delivery style. You feel like you're sitting at the coffee shop chatting, which is pretty cool. For me, it was a good reminder to determine what is important to you and to focus on being present. That is something that I struggle with as I am pretty consistently consuming information from a device whenever I am anywhere. I'm not sure of a fix for that yet though, because learning and information are pretty high on the list of things that are important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Evie Shaffer' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/evie_shaffer.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Evie Shaffer&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Evie shared from a different background, but had a similar theme: Make a careful explanation of who you are and focus on that. To reenforce the point, she shared ways of finding the 'sweet spot' which for her was a happy mix of doing work that allowed for artful expression and had a purpose. She emphasized that doing the work is way more important than the tools that you have to do it and shared a list of things to be wary of and to embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;What Sucks Life:&lt;/strong&gt;
          prestige, pride, conforming and comparing yourself to others
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;What Gives Life:&lt;/strong&gt;
          curiosity, mindfulness, limitations, simplicity, adversity and passion
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Evie also had a very relaxed, conversational style. I especially enjoyed the talk of mindfulness as that is something that I have been studying for the last few months. One interesting thing that left me thinking was that she highly recommended reading over watching TV for learning. Assuming that we're not comparing watching Family Guy to reading about history, this left me really thinking about why. I'd be willing to bet that most people would recommend reading a book on Egyptian history over watching a documentary. Is it primarily a matter of being able to pause and think while consuming information or are there vast cognitive differences between being taught visually vs. reading? This will be important as we are introducing more visual and interactive ways of learning into our schools.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Joshua Blankenship' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/joshua_blankenship.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Joshua Blankenship&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Joshua is a wizard and so are you. His talk was a wonderful reminder that what we do is magic. By magic, he means that we have great power to make things happen and that to anyone that has not done our type of work that is what it feels like. He shared the story of his work with Newspring Church and called for us to step back from what we do at times to realize how wonderful it is. 'When was the last time you were awestruck?' Take the time to realize how amazing things are because we are building the future but it doesn't feel like that today. It often feels like we are struggling in the present. Use your powers to build things as you want them to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Joshua is a storyteller and his delivery was great. I'm guessing that he is a great inspiration to anyone trying to make their way as he is highly talented, but lightly reminds everyone that he comes from a humble town in a state that 'dukes it out with Mississippi for 49th/50th in education'. Specifically, he reminded me to keep working and researching as he shared a quote from Kevin Kelly: 'Out of these inefficient tinkerings will come the future.' On a lighter note, I loved the term 'black market graphics' which are things that are created outside of the design team for a brand.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Paul Sirmon' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/paul_sirmon.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Paul Sirmon&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Paul shared tips and process for working on the branding of non-profits. He walked us through his process of 'showing them what they want and then showing them what they need'. The walkthrough of the creation of a mark for RU4 Children was very interesting as was his description of a popular problem in the flow for branding. He shared a triangle representing a good flow where brand thoughts begin at the organizational level, move to identity and then onto experiential. The common problem is that the beginning of projects is often inverted which leads to problems in the long run. Properly determining who you are, what you do and how you will do it will lead to the visual identity.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Paul had a very conversational style and it was interesting to hear about his process of creating a visual identity. I really resonated with the inverted approach to creating a brand element as I did this with the logo for the Front-End Design Conference. It was entirely based on the appearance of the original site concept and I've been shaking my head at it ever since because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Noah Stokes' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/noah_stokes.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Noah Stokes&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Noah's talk was all about the pForm, which is the formula for a good pop song. I'm kidding, but it definitely was a cool part. I took the least amount of notes during his talk because it was a great story. Aside from the pForm, it wasn't structured in a way to grab bullet points or quotes but it was totally engaging. It was wonderful to hear how each of his experiences were different, but taught him things that led to the path he is on right now. From working on devices at Apple to Palm (where Apple engineers go to die) to creating websites.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Noah is one of those people that you instantly look up to and not just because he's taller than you. He is a great storyteller and just comes off as this genuinely great dude. My favorite quote from his talk and one of the few notes that I took was 'HTML/CSS is the next best thing to designing.' This is exactly how I feel as I love creating beautiful designs but am not very skilled in the graphic design area. So, doing markup for them keeps me satisfied both with the challenge of writing the  code and with creating great designs.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Promise Tangeman' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/promise_tangeman.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Promise Tangeman&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Promise kicked things off with something that I hadn't seen before, a highlight reel of her work. It was really cool and we got to see a bunch of samples of the type of work that she has done for people that weren't already fans. The main theme of her presentation was to evaluate  what you put into your mind and establish a diet. She shared some quotes that have inspired her along the way and the ways that she steps away from things to make sure to stay focused.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: Promise shared a lot of great quotes and Cherrie and I are big fans of her work. It was cool to hear the story of how she had someone that she felt competitive with but reached out to have coffee with despite the possible uncomfort. It led to a long-running relationship where they now critique each other's work and help each other grow.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Dan Mall' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/dan_mall.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Dan Mall&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
          Dan shared with us some fantastic stories of getting through projects and different ways of communicating with clients. He emphasized the value of making clients part of the team and how the success of projects hinders on how well you do. He shared some fantastic projects with Star Wars and Lego and how that and the use of the adjacent possible helped them. The 'adjacent possible' which is (loosely) using a solution from an unrelated problem to solve something you are working on. Also, this:
          &lt;a href='http://mostawesomestthingever.com'&gt;mostawesomestthingever.com&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: I was especially looking forward to Dan's talk as I saw him speak at the first conference I attended, FOWD NYC 2008. He is a wonderful storyteller and I have always dug his way of sharing information. It was hard to take notes because I was enjoying the story so much, but the client suggestions and adjacent possible parts were great. I loved the whole talk.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;After Party&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Day one wrapped up and we had some time to kill before the party, so Chris Wallace showed us this fantastic Italian place. We had a great dinner with him and some other awesome folks. The after party was at this wonderful wine place with a great patio. Big thank you to&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;a href='http://mailchimp.com'&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;
    for sponsoring that and making it happen. We had a great time chatting with some great folks and got to hang with Lain to thank Mailchimp for the good times. He was a lot of fun. Overall, it was a great time with great conversations.
    &lt;h2&gt;Day Two Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;ul class='circles-talks'&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Kevin Richardson' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/kevin_richardson.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kevin Richardson&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Kevin started day two off with a bang, with great stories and taking chances and living life. Overall, the theme was &quot;be bold with your life and be bold with your career&quot;. At one point in his life, he wondered why all of the other people get to do amazing things and he wasn't. So, he started making big changes and hasn't stopped. There were lots of hard times and scary decisions, but he is extremely happy.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: This was one of the most inspirational talks. Kevin's energy, combined with the fact that he has taken risks despite normally wanting be comfortable was awesome. This one struck me personally because my life greatly changed and I have 'lived' so much more since meeting Cherrie. She has inspired drive in me and led me around the world experiencing wonderful things. It was cool that Kevin's inspiration also came from his love.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Ismael Burciaga' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/ismael_burciaga.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Ismael Burciaga aka Ish&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ish shared how he has 'spilled blood' throughout his career in order to inspire everyone working on growing their skills. It was really brave to get up in front of the crowd and share screens of his early work. Seeing the progression of his skills and having him share that it came from a combination of doing lots of work, reading good books and reaching out to mentors was just so awesome. Plus, we got to see a bunch of great work.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: I have a big fan of Ish's work for a while and it was so fantastic to see the progression of his work. It reminded me to just keep doing work, reading and getting feedback. It was also awesome that he reminded everyone to seek inspiration from outside of the web and bring good ideas from the world to it.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Blaine Hogan' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/blaine_hogan.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Blaine Hogan&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Blaine wants to be sure you know that you are not a tool. His presentation was about becoming a better human, all the while admitting that it is even hard for him to step back from work. It was a great talk with a few really important steps: relax, breathe and embrace the obstacles. He also shared this very touching video from his work with his church.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: The most important part for me was the reminder to step back and ask yourself 'what am I really making'? It's a cool thought that will help you from just acting like a tool.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Jonathan Moore' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/jonathan_moore.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Jonathan Moore&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Jonathan's talk was about the internal thoughts of doing creative work. It was full of great nuggets like: happiness is 90% internal and success is based on your particular lense. One great tip was when you are overwhelmed on a project to just start creating. Then, make it awesome with each step. He emphasizes that when working with a client, your ultimate goal is to make them a hero in their organization.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: I had a little nostalgic fanboy moment when he shared that he was part of the 2advanced team at one point. They were such a huge inspiration to me wanting to work on the web. He had another cool little thought about the type of work that we do: &quot;Try something reckless. No one is going to die.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Phil Coffman' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/phil_coffman.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Phil Coffman&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Phil shared his story, which was very inspirational to anyone getting started in the industry. After a weird little stint being a general manager of a web shop as his first job in the industry, he began doing very 'regular' work for a company. He did everything for them from mugs to web work. He shared how he progressed through the job and did things on the side which ultimately led to where he is at now.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: It was really great to hear his backstory and to see another person that got successful by just cranking through work and doing side projects. It was a great example of how hard work and knocking out things that come your way leads to great things. I'll be sure to point him out to anyone that I meet that is just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;div class='container'&gt;
        &lt;div class='circles-speaker'&gt;
          &lt;img alt='Cameron Moll' src='/images/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012/cameron_moll.png' /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cameron Moll&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Cameron shared some information about how non-profits can make it easier for for-profit companies to help their cause. His main points were: make it transparent, make it attractive and make it matter. He shared his story about helping Charity: Water and his trip to Africa to see the results. Then he tugged at our heart strings with some really touching videos. They were wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My take: It was a sobering reminder of how lucky I am. Seeing videos of the people in Africa walking miles for water and consuming from pools of water formed in the dirt was very powerful. Cameron did a great job of sharing ways to help as well.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Hanging Out&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cherrie and I were very lucky to tag along to dinner with an awesome mix of Ish, the speakers and the 2 folks that helped get us home each night: Mina Markham and Chris Wallace. On top of being this fantastic barbecue place, I got to chat in a group of people for hours with Dan Mall. This registers pretty high on the fanboy scoreboard. He reenforced all my high thoughts of him as he was generally interested in learning more about everyone and sharing. It was a great time.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Circles Conference 2012 was truly inspirational and I want to congratulate Ish on a job well done. You would have never known that it was his first event. Everything was so well done and looked amazing. I'd like to specifically thank Micah for giving Code School a shout out on the stage, which led to me getting to meet some great people. Extra special thank you to Mina Markham and Chris Wallace. To Mina for hanging with us and bringing us back to the hotel Thursday night. To Chris for hanging with us and driving us all around Dallas to get us back to the hotel on Friday night. Oh and some advice: if you travel to Dallas do not stay at a hotel at the airport. They charge the taxis $18 to leave the lot which makes your fare a minimum of $25 no matter where you go.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Keep an eye out for when Ish gets some rest and to see when he will run his next event. Then get your tickets before they sell out. If you're interested in following up and learning more about the speakers, check out the
      &lt;a href='http://circlesconference.com/#sectionSpeakers'&gt;Circles Conference site.&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;div class='post-standard-signature'&gt;
        &lt;small&gt;September 22, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div id='disqus_thread'&gt;
      &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
      var disqus_shortname = 'dandenney';
      (function() {
      var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
      dsq.src = 'http://' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
      (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
      })();
      &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com&quot; class=&quot;dsq-brlink&quot;&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class=&quot;logo-disqus&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;link href='/stylesheets/posts/conferences/circles-conference-2012.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Attitude Reflect Leadership, Captain</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/attitude-reflect-leadership-captain"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/attitude-reflect-leadership-captain</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend, Cherrie and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist watching Remember the Titans when we came across it on TV. It&amp;rsquo;s such a fantastic story. Anyhow, there is this one scene when the two future leaders square off about the issues with the team. Bertier says that Julius' &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna get mine&amp;rdquo; attitude is all wrong. Julius replies with &amp;ldquo;attitude reflect leadership, Captain&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is so true. While his was said in a negative time, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing how awesome it can be in good times. I&amp;rsquo;m the happiest that I have ever been professionally working with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://envylabs.com&quot;&gt;Envy Labs&lt;/a&gt; team. My attitude is absolutely reflecting the leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are technically a flat company, there are leaders and they rock. There will never be a time where everyone agrees with every direction or decision, but the leadership at Envy is fantastic. They all have a great mix of leading by example: inspiring with high aspirations while maintaining a relaxed demeanor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They raise up the whole team and encourage us to be better (people in general) as well as better employees.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>I Love Kippt</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/i-love-kippt"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/i-love-kippt</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Twitter addict for a few years now. The primary reason that I am addicted is that it is my main way of discovering things related to front-end work. Of course, I dig the social part of having tweetversations but the links are my main reason for going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kippt.com&quot;&gt;Kippt&lt;/a&gt; has provided the best UI and UX that I have seen for link collectors like myself. It is a gorgeous site and has all of the right features for quickly organizing and discovering links. It is a fantastic design and I love it. So, I&amp;rsquo;m dedicating extra time each day to build up &lt;a href=&quot;https://kippt.com/dandenney&quot;&gt;my collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Execution is All That Matters</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/execution-is-all-that-matters"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/thoughts/execution-is-all-that-matters</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working in the &amp;lsquo;online world&amp;rsquo;, it is hard to not have multiple ideas per day on things that you would like to create. More than anything else, what I have learned is that execution is all that matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shipping is vital. It&amp;rsquo;s not the only thing that matters, but getting your idea into something that people can interact with has to be your number one goal. How you execute (along with some or the random market stuff) will determine how successful your idea is, but you can&amp;rsquo;t know how well you execute until you actually do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought this many times, but I&amp;rsquo;m writing based on Brad Frost&amp;rsquo;s recent release: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.github.com/this-is-responsive&quot;&gt;This is Responsive&lt;/a&gt;. I had an idea for something like this and grabbed up a domain (responsv.com) for it. I had an idea, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great part is that the world now has a site like this. Brad has put in a ton of work on it already and it is going to be fantastic. He did some really cool stuff like putting lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/bradfrost&quot;&gt;code samples on Codepen&lt;/a&gt;. He has a lot of swagger in the responsive group, so I think it is probably better to have someone like him behind this project. I love seeing the great reaction and the numbers on Codepen because it confirms that I at least have ideas for things that people will dig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is good and it is getting me moving on my one idea that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to kick out of my brain for the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>See Nick Preprocess</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/see-nick-preprocess"/>
 		<updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/see-nick-preprocess</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;div class='columns-two'&gt;
  &lt;div class='column'&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      Alright
      &lt;br /&gt;
      Stop whatcha doin'
      &lt;br /&gt;
      'cause Nick's about to ruin
      &lt;br /&gt;
      the way of writin' styles that ya used to.
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;
      You can save the time of reading this and just
      &lt;a href='http://www.codeschool.com/courses/assembling-sass'&gt;get started learning Sass&lt;/a&gt;
      from Nick on Code School if you like.
    &lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='column'&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Nick Walsh' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/see-nick-preprocess/nick-walsh.png' /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We launched Assembling Sass today at Code School.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have been pumped about
  &lt;a href='http://www.codeschool.com/courses/assembling-sass'&gt;this course&lt;/a&gt;
  since I got hired on. It took me about 10 minutes to fall in love with Sass once I was lucky enough to have Michael Parenteau show me how to get started.
  In Assembling Sass, Nick Walsh will be showing you a bunch of rad stuff that Sass can do and how it will help with your workflow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You should be using a preprocessor.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course, I recommend Sass and definitely recommend taking the course that Nick put together but the main thing is that you should really start using one. Start small, get a site converted over to one and just learn as you go. I was hesitant and just sat around reading articles about how cool they are for too long. You really won't understand how useful they are until you dive in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, here are the benefits of using Sass in my own words. Fortunately, you'll learn all of these in
  &lt;a href='http://www.codeschool.com/courses/assembling-sass'&gt;Assembling Sass.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will write less code.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In vanilla CSS, you continually have to repeat things with the same meaning and you have to be redundant. (wink, wink) For real, though, how many times have you duplicated a class name to style containing elements? .nav li, .nav a .nav a span, etc. Nesting allows for a clean organization for things like that so you'll only write the .nav once. I'm simplifying the benefit, but that alone is enough reason to use a preprocessor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will copy and paste less.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  How many times can you copy and paste vendor prefixes before you go insane? I don't know the number yet, but thankfully I rarely do it anymore so I will get there more slowly. Mixins and @extend drastically reduce the amount of copying and pasting that you have to do within your stylesheet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You can share styles.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Have you ever wanted something to share the same style of something else, but different? You know, like you want the button to have the same rounded corners, border and colors but a larger font or a different font. I always wished that rather than adding classes to things in the HTML that I could just call a class in another class in my stylesheet. That is what @extend does, so no more pitching coins into the mall fountain for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will learn to write better code.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Once you stray away from the workflow of repeating elements, copying and pasting, chaining elements, etc. you will begin to focus more on your organization. Once you're organized, you'll look for other ways to improve your code. The programmatic benefits of Sass are tremendous. There are many ways to to get creative and make your code work for you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  You will get to results more
  &lt;strike&gt;
    raptorly
  &lt;/strike&gt;
  rapidly.
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Designing in the browser and rapid prototyping are not just buzz words, they are new workflows as a front-end dev. More and more, things are getting into the browser and markup earlier. Using a combination of variables and built-in functions, you can alter the appearance of a site very quickly. Store a few colors and use color functions like lighten and darken on them and you can completely change the look of a site in seconds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Nested media queries will become one of your best friends if you do any responsive work. Rather than bouncing around to different media query zones, you can nest them directly with elements. This is very important when you are making changes for when the design breaks instead of using set breakpoints.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Also, you won't do math anymore. No more calculator or cool generator that someone lovingly put hours and hours of work into. You simply let Sass do the math. No need to figure out what percentage 248px is of 1024px and paste in an answer when you can just put them in something like this:
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;width: percentage(248px / 1024px)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ok, I'm done twisting your arm.
  &lt;a href='http://www.codeschool.com/courses/assembling-sass'&gt;Go try out Level 1 for free.&lt;/a&gt;
  If you're not a Code School user, that will let you decide on whether or not you dig the teaching style and want to sign up to take the course (and any others).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you want to read a more professionally written preprocessor pitch article, check out
  &lt;a href='http://cognition.happycog.com/article/preprocess-this'&gt;Preprocess THIS!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Whatever you do now, start using a preprocessor. If you try it for a month and don't like it, I'll buy you beers to help drown your sorrows of forever writing vanilla CSS.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Playing With CSS Hat</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-css-hat"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-css-hat</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;link href='/stylesheets/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-css-hat.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
&lt;article class='post' id='playing-with-css-hat'&gt;
  &lt;div class='wrapper'&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Playing with CSS Hat&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href='http://csshat.com'&gt;CSS Hat&lt;/a&gt;
      is a photoshop plugin from the team that will hopefully bring us
      &lt;a href='http://csspiffle.com'&gt;CSS Pifffle.&lt;/a&gt;
      I had been anxiously awaiting for it to be released because I wanted to see what the team was capable of. They are currently working on a new app for web creation, intended to replace Photoshop and Fireworks for us.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;It surprised me&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I was skeptical because most things that automate code output some crazy ish. The code that comes out of CSS Hat is very usable. I'd prefer if there was a way to alphabetize the properties as an option, but I have
      &lt;a href='http://procssor.com'&gt;procssor&lt;/a&gt;
      for that. I'm using Compass or Sass mixins a lot these days so I wouldn't necessarily copy and paste the code at all. To me, it is a quick way to get the nitty gritty stuff: hex codes, opacity percentages, shadow ratios, etc.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Building something with it&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A while ago I had this little dream that every day I would code out a psd resource from sites like 365psd and share them as a gallery. I didn't follow through, but I did do one. So, I'm going to compare that with what I can grab straight out of the psd.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='light'&gt;
    &lt;div class='container'&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Original Image&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;img alt='Day 155 nav from 365psd' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-css-hat/day155.png' /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Original Conversion&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;div class='day155'&gt;
          &lt;div id='code-version'&gt;
            &lt;nav&gt;
              &lt;a class='first' href='#'&gt;Day&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;a href='#'&gt;Week&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;a href='#'&gt;Month&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;a class='last' href='#'&gt;List&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/nav&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class='container'&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;CSS Hat Version&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;div class='csshat'&gt;
          &lt;nav&gt;
            &lt;a class='first' href='#'&gt;Day&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Week&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Month&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a class='last' href='#'&gt;List&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/nav&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;With a little padding&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;div class='csshat padded'&gt;
          &lt;nav&gt;
            &lt;a class='first' href='#'&gt;Day&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Week&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Month&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a class='last' href='#'&gt;List&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/nav&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='wrapper'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Ok, so it's not plug and play&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      This particular psd brings out some flaws, but not necessarily flaws with CSS Hat. It's more of a general flaw in using Photoshop to make things intended to be built with CSS. Here is the error the notes from CSS Hat:
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
        *Stroke has a gradient fill type, but there is no way to express that in CSS, writing the average color instead. Blending modes are used in gradient fill and inner shadow, but they are impossible to realistically transfer to CSS.
      &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Our designer used blending modes which are not CSS friendly. It's not that you can't replicate the end result, it's that there is no way to automate it. You can't (yet with browser support) set something like &quot;blendmode: overlay;&quot;.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      When I originally coded up my version, I spent a good deal of time with the eyedropper trying to nail down the colors for the beginning and end colors for the gradients.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      There are a couple of things that you could grab from the outputted code, like the border-radius for example. Other than that, though, the blending modes killed this one. As you can see there are some other things that you'd have to use tools to get too. The padding, for example, would have to come from using rulers or something. (I use
      &lt;a href='http://iconfactory.com/software/xscope'&gt;xScope&lt;/a&gt;
      for all measuring and colors now.) As usual, fonts are off as well. It calls for a 13px Helvetica Neue Bold but I changed it to normal.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='wrapper'&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Build something without blending modes&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I wanted to try something without blending modes to see how it works out. It gets better, but you'll see there are still some issues.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='light'&gt;
    &lt;div class='container'&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Original Image&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;img alt='200 Days of Awesomeness #4' src='/images/posts/front-end-dev/playing-with-css-hat/200days-4.png' /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class='sample'&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;CSS Hat Styles&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;div class='awesome-4'&gt;
          &lt;nav&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;a href='#'&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/nav&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='container'&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Now I made some quick tweaks to get it in the range of the original. Padding, margin, font-family, font-size, max-width, etc.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='light'&gt;
    &lt;div class='container'&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;With quick adjustments&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class='awesome-4 adjusted'&gt;
        &lt;nav&gt;
          &lt;a href='#'&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href='#'&gt;Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href='#'&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href='#'&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/nav&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='wrapper'&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      You can see that it missed some of the details. The thin stroke didn't make it in correctly and the gradient color shifted a bit. The stroke is just a matter of needing it to be 2 pixels inside the element and 1px around and I'm guessing the gradient issue is that a scale of 28% was used. I bet they're not set up to grab scaling gradients.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Final thought: It's ok&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      So it's on the way but as it is, it can only be used as a shortcut to getting some of the property values. It still leaves me hopeful for their upcoming tool. I imagine if all of the options within the tool had to have a direct CSS equivalent, there would be much better accuracy. For me, it's $20 so if it saves me at least 30 minutes (ever) it was worth the price of admission.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;July 21, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Production vs. Shipping</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/production-vs-shipping"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/production-vs-shipping</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;small&gt;I try not to 'rock the boat' too often. However, it is impossible to share this post without pointing out the differences in the cultures that I have worked in during my first few years in the web design industry. Out of respect for the ones that aren't getting the best review, I don't want to name names of the companies. I want to be sure to say that I have also had a couple positions with great company cultures that ended for other reasons.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early exposure to web design and front-end development as a profession was more of a culture of 'production first'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Production First Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 'production first', I mean that producing something as a deliverable is the number one priority. While this might not be stated outright, it is created by the guidelines by which you work. There were positions that felt that at all times my hand should be on the keyboard or a mouse and in a tool that produces a deliverable. Research was a secondary option and it would usually be offered with the words &quot;spend a couple of minutes&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesson I learned: My time at work is meant to be producing something. Research and efficiency are not as important as the fact that you are currently manipulating something into a deliverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To grow my skills, I had to spend time outside of work reading, doing tutorials, attending events and doing online training. I would leave work and read about how all of these other companies and people work. I would read that people talked with their co-workers about projects (outside of client meetings), sketched things while 'on the clock', took breaks when they were stuck on something (even doing fun things like ping pong or video games), paired with another person (where they both figured out a code solution together) and many other examples. So, I would read about these and then I would go back to work and not be able to apply any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The White Whale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of positions with 'production first' company cultures, I started to question the things posted online. It began to feel like these companies were like unicorns or Bigfoot. Luckily, I get around to a lot of events and had great conversations with people that confirmed that some of these things were real. However, that left me 'chasing the white whale'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I found one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now that I found one I feel compelled to share. I want everyone to know that not only do these companies exist, there's at least one here in Florida (where 4 out of my 5 blog readers live. Hi, mom.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A 'Shipping Culture'&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now work at Envy Labs, which is based in Orlando. I would say that their culture has a focus on 'shipping'. In a shipping culture, the focus is a lot more holistic. While deliverables are the ultimate goal, everything involved in that process is important because it all affects how efficiently you ship and the quality of the things that you ship. It's doing things in the right way, but also choosing the right things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example: In a 'production first' culture, you may deal with network latency or slow tools for months or years in the name of getting things done. In a 'shipping culture', you dedicate some time to have things run better. (Recently at Code School, we had 2 devs jump off of other tasks in order to upgrade Ruby. Now the app runs faster for everyone that touches it locally. These guys spent some time working on a non-deliverable that makes everyone on the team get to a deliverable more efficiently.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the things that affect the overall process as I have seen them so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Work space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a beautiful office, located in the heart of downtown Orlando and on the 20th floor of a tower. There are separate rooms for types of work being done: design, project management and development. Then there are shared spaces like the couches, kitchen and ping pong 'arena'. (Oh and remember about the mystical practice of pairing? We have a room dedicated to anyone doing that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with all of these things you would think that maybe they do it to make sure that people are there all day. Nope. It's up to you when you work in the office. I can tell you firsthand that the combination of the people, the amenities and the freedom make me want to be in the office every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything about the company is wide open for discussion amongst the team. We have weekly standups where this communication is planned as well as some optional team building times like Whiskey Wednesdays or Free Lunch Fridays. The bulk of the communication happens online, though, via Campfire and Basecamp. This transparency makes me already feel like part of the team and that it would be perfectly ok for me to ask any question about projects, the team, financials, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Building&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination of a fantastic workspace and dedicated time to team building and transparency results in a desire to be part of the team. You want to be there and you want to help out others because you feel like you are a part of something special. You could think that this is just me being new, but I routinely see requests for help (or even task swapping) go into Campfire and they are fulfilled with the quickness. Plus, I witnessed the team knocking out to-dos and fixing things in support for Code School customers throughout the 4th of July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Paid to Think&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now paid to think. Think first, then do what is the best solution or what will lead you to the best solution. Then, ship it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I want to share how this works specifically related to the front-end side of things but I thought I should break up the posts a bit. If you're interested, check out:
  &lt;a href='/posts/front-end-dev/mondays-rock/'&gt;Mondays Rock&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;July 16, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Mondays Rock</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/mondays-rock"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/mondays-rock</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mondays have a tendency to suck in most jobs. As I've been bragging, though, I now work for a company that does things a little differently. I wake up at 6 a.m., get ready and drive 2 hours over to Orlando on Mondays now and I'm happy to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Now I'm not sure if this is a routine thing, but the past 3 Mondays have started off with
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/nickawalsh'&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt;
  showing us how to do something rad.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A bit of an adjustment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front-end dev team here thinks things through and implements things in a very smart way. It is the type of atmosphere that I have been dying to be a part of. I wish I could say that I harnessed a bunch of Chi and instantly became part of the think tank. Not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What if someone sees us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  On one of our recent Mondays, Nick wanted to share the process for creating a slider for a project we're working on. So he,
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/drewbarontini'&gt;Drew&lt;/a&gt;
  and I paired to work on it. As Drew and I were sitting behind him, I couldn't help being a little uneasy. &quot;What if someone sees us not typing something, but instead huddled around a computer.&quot; Well, everyone that walked in saw us because we have glass walls. The boss man, Gregg, saw us and waved 'good morning' to us on his way in. That was that. No checking in to see what was preventing us from typing, no casual recommendation to get back to producing something or to only spend a couple minutes with this (as I have experienced in my past). Wow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The benefits of this approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular slider, an optimistic estimate for me to do it on my own would have been a couple of hours. Getting it into CoffeeScript would have added a bit since I'm new to that too. Instead, WE WROTE CODE ON A WHITEBOARD AND TALKED THROUGH IT. It was so cool. We talked through how this particular slider needed to work, named things on the board and worked it out in our heads and on the whiteboard. Then Nick typed it up and we worked through the kinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd say we probably spent about 30 minutes or so together, though I'm sure Nick had spent some time thinking through it in advance. Either way, it was at worst a 'wash' on the time I would have spent. (Considering 3 of us at 30ish minutes instead of me at 2 hours.) However, rather than me knocking my way through it and then Nick and/or Drew having to figure out what I did whenever they had to work with it, we all knew how it worked. Any time now, I can jump into the slider and make sense of it very quickly as we all agreed on the function and the naming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this week Nick showed us some awesome that he cooked up for handling a unique carousel. It involved some very logical thinking and honestly it was way over my head. Nick is a programmer in disguise, IMHO. The rad thing is that he applies programmatic thinking to front-end solutions and Drew and I get to benefit from it. So, again I spent a little time behind Nick as he explained how to dynamically assign absolute positioning to a list of items and to assign classes to smooth things out. Fifteen minutes (or less) of brain dumping that makes me reimagine how to approach things and expanded my understanding of logical JS and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stand-up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the fun, we do a company and then a project stand-up. Monday is a fantastic day for this, in my opinion, because you kick off the week sharing what you're going to do and then you go ship that ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not just Mondays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The design/front-end side of things isn't just awesome on Mondays but they stand out so much that they were worth sharing. Drew has shared that he codes more in his head than he does in his editor. He and Nick have cherry picked a bunch of things from the various CSS processes and
  &lt;a href='http://mvcss.github.com/MVCSS/'&gt;shared their collection&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/jasonvanlue'&gt;Jason&lt;/a&gt;
  thinks through everything and is one of the most pragmatic people that I have met. (As an aside, he is going through some stuff. So if you are the kind that offers thoughts or prayers for wonderful people, give him and his health a mention in your next round please.)
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/justinmezzell'&gt;Justin&lt;/a&gt;
  is just crazy good at visual communication. Hearing him talk through how to communicate something and seeing the end product is fantastic. There are little things that I probably shouldn't be so excited about but that I am. They use dashes instead of underscores for naming, they alphabetize CSS properties and they don't bind themselves to a complicated CSS grid structure. All huge plusses for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Think before you code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I am now working on being as cool as all of them. I was hired on to a team of thinkers and I'm working on breaking my production-first training. It bit me a little last week as I tried to get to having a viewable item too quickly in some HTML email stuff, but I'm fixing that. The best part is that I have 4 fantastic people to learn from immediately and an awesome team of people beyond them making everything else rock as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;July 16, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Growing with Envy</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/general/growing-with-envy"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/general/growing-with-envy</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently signed on with the Envy Labs team as a front-end dev to work on projects including Code School. This is a little post sharing how big of a change this is for me and how excited I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I found my Wufoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ever since I met the whole
  &lt;a href='http://wufoo.com/about'&gt;Wufoo team&lt;/a&gt;
  at one of their weekly scrums, I've been saying that I wanted to &quot;find my Wufoo&quot;. I was wowed by how they were a team of extremely talented individuals that worked together on a product that they cared about.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have known of
  &lt;a href='http://envylabs.com'&gt;Envy Labs&lt;/a&gt;
  for a while and paid attention to their client projects, community outreach and the team. What I've found in my first week is that they have all of the things that I have admired about that Wufoo team and they also work on a product that I love:
  &lt;a href='http://codeschool.com'&gt;Code School&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='columns'&gt;
  &lt;div class='column'&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;A team that rocks&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Envy Labs' src='/images/posts/general/growing-with-envy/envy-labs.png' /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      I am both intimidated and excited to be working on this team. It is comprised of highly talented and passionate people with varied skills. The best part, for me, is that I am working directly with 2 kickass front-end devs (
      &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/nickawalsh'&gt;Nick Walsh&lt;/a&gt;
      and
      &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/#!/drewbarontini'&gt;Drew Barontini&lt;/a&gt;
      with
      &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/jasonvanlue'&gt;Mr. Jason VanLue&lt;/a&gt;
      on the dizigns.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='column'&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;A product that I love&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Code School' src='/images/posts/general/growing-with-envy/code-school.png' /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love the web and the people that build it. So, contributing to a team that is helping to improve the skills of builders is a dream come true. Code School has been my favorite of the online training options and now I get to actually work on it. There are so many great things in the works!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Amazing culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I know that words like 'awesome' and 'amazing' get thrown around a lot, but I am really amazed. I had no idea that there were web companies with a culture like this in Florida. The way projects are formed and assigned, the location, the internal communication and the amenities are all top-notch. It is truly a special company and I am already so proud to be a part of it. Honors go to
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/greggpollack'&gt;Greg Pollack&lt;/a&gt;
  for putting it all together and keeping it going.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a heads-up before I started about the tech that the front-end team uses so I jumped into learning Haml and Coffeescript. In a week, I'm already working writing Haml pretty comfortably. I can read Coffeescript but haven't written any yet outside of earning the badge. (We did have an awesome pairing session this morning, though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm diving back into using Terminal more and learned a bit more about setting up local Rails instances. On top of this, I have learned a ton just by listening to the way that the team communicates and discusses problems to solve. I can't even fathom where my skill level will be in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='columns'&gt;
  &lt;a class='column' href='http://startupquote.com/post/4799610682'&gt;
    &lt;img alt='Hiten Shah quote - you make your own luck. Every single minute of every day.' src='/images/posts/general/growing-with-envy/hiten-shah.png' /&gt;
    Startupquotes.com
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class='column'&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;How I got here and why I'm sharing&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So, the point of this post wasn't to boast about how rad of a job I landed. It was to share how fantastic things can be for you.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As Hiten Shah says: &quot;You make your own luck. Every single minute of every day&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Make your own luck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took 4 web-related jobs across 4 years, a few bouts with freelancing, over 10k tweets, attending a bunch of events, doing lots of online training, reading thousands of articles, reading dozens of books and running 4 conferences to figure out what I wanted and come across an opportunity for it. (Oh, and responding in the right way to one DM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, it took leaving people that I really cared about at those jobs in pursuit of another opportunity closer to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want everyone to have the job that they're dreaming of. Keep sharpening your skills and be mindful of the things that really make you excited when you're working. Then, make your own luck! If you ever need a little inspiration, just watch Gary V's talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='' frameborder='0' height='516' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/EhqZ0RU95d4' width='688'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Oh and I know an
  &lt;a href='http://codeschool.com'&gt;awesome service for sharpening your coding skills&lt;/a&gt;
  when you're ready to get going. (wink, wink)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='post-standard-signature'&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;July 2, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;link href='/stylesheets/posts/general/growing-with-envy.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>HTML but with an A and Less Code</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/HTML-but-with-an-a-and-less-code"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/HTML-but-with-an-a-and-less-code</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;This is just me sharing as I learn something, definitely not a tutorial.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;HTML, but with an A and less code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  What do you do when you're joining a team that actually has &quot;Mr. Haml&quot; on it? Well, you spend some time learning Haml. (To be clear, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/nickawalsh&quot;&gt;Nick Walsh&lt;/a&gt; didn't create Haml, he just has been dubbed that by the front-end team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://envylabs.com&quot;&gt;Envy Labs&lt;/a&gt; because he &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netmagazine.com/tutorials/craft-cleaner-more-concise-html-haml&quot;&gt;wrote about it for .Net&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://futureofwebdesign.com/new-york-2011/speakers/&quot;&gt;spoke on it at FOWD NYC 2011&lt;/a&gt;. In Nick's words, Haml is a way to craft cleaner, more concise HTML.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Haml and Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Originally created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://hamptoncatlin.com&quot;&gt;Hampton Catlin&lt;/a&gt;, Haml is an HTML preprocessor that is primarily used in Rails apps. Normally, you would just use a .haml extension on a file in a Rails app and it just works. However, if you want to play with it elsewhere you can have it work immediately with &lt;a href=&quot;http://incident57.com/codekit/&quot;&gt;Codekit&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Not to toot my own horn too much, but I am really pleased that I have just redone my site without a CMS. The main reason being that this post is actually being written in Haml in order to learn it. Because I didn't bind myself to templates, I can craft up this entire page in Haml and not have to worry about the rest of the site. (I'm not sure about how I will keep the nav updated dynamically but I'll broach that as we go.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building this post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, first things first I need a document structure. Now I could read a bit about how to set one up in the docs but I thought I'd just follow what Nick and Drew put together for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mvcss/MVCSS&quot;&gt;MVCSS&lt;/a&gt;. That was super easy to follow to get the basic page structure rolling. Then, I tried sharing the code in here and that gets a little &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=cray+cray&quot;&gt;cray, cray&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1993993/haml-with-pre-how-to-remove-unwanted-intend#_=_&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; on the wonderful Stack Overflow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So this below is what it takes to build up a basic page ready for content, pulling in my sitewide CSS and &lt;a href=&quot;http://typekit.com&quot;&gt;Typekit&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-markup'&gt;!!! 5&amp;#x000A;%html{:lang =&gt; &quot;en&quot;}&amp;#x000A;	%head&amp;#x000A;		%meta(http-equiv='X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge,chrome=1')&amp;#x000A;		%meta(charset='utf-8')&amp;#x000A;		%meta(name='viewport' content='width=device-width,initial-scale=1')&amp;#x000A;		%title &quot;HTML, but with an A and less code&quot;&amp;#x000A;		%link(href=&quot;/stylesheets/screen.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;)&amp;#x000A;	%body&amp;#x000A;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  On save, Codekit does it's magic compiling and this is what gets created:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-markup'&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang='en'&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;meta http-equiv='X-UA-Compatible&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;IE=edge,chrome=1'&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;meta charset='utf-8'&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width,initial-scale=1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&amp;quot;HTML, but with an A and less code&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;link href='/stylesheets/screen.css' rel='stylesheet'&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It took a little bit to get there and to figure out the rules on indenting, but it is mighty clean code and I get the feeling that the &amp;lt; and &amp;gt; keys are going to be getting a little bit of a break as I work more in Haml.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As I was looking for solutions, I found this article about why you &lt;a href=&quot;http://chriseppstein.github.com/blog/2010/02/08/haml-sucks-for-content/&quot;&gt;shouldn't be using Haml for content&lt;/a&gt;. While I'm doing the exact opposite as I learn the ins-and-outs of it, there are some cool things about Haml in that article. Basically, you can decide how you want to write your content. Use haml for your structure and pop in raw HTML as needed, use markdown, textile, etc. That is pretty cool.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So far, this part has been easy but links are a little tricky. Getting in some of the special HTML5 items like icons called by data values with entities and aria-hidden are giving me some challenges. I'll follow up with the rest of the page shortly because I don't want to share where I have regular HTML mixed in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
  June 24, 2012
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving to Codepen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I wanted to share the whole bit of code in here but it actually makes a lot more sense if you can see it in action. So, I popped &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/dandenney/pen/4/2&quot;&gt; the whole post up on Codepen.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  You won't get the fonts from Typekit but I popped the CSS in there, so you can get to see the style. I'd recommend making the HTML panel the whole window and then toggling to the HAML link in there to see the HTML. It'll be much better than what you would see in here. You can edit the code and play with different sections to see what compiles and you'll get some fun with Haml errors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Thanks for checking this out, I'm sorry if it wasn't very informative. This was more a way to practice a new skill and type my way through it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
  June 26, 2012
&lt;/small&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>A Sass Noob using Math for Flexible Widths</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/a-sass-noob-using-math-for-flexible-widths"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/a-sass-noob-using-math-for-flexible-widths</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;article class='post-standard'&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;A Sass Noob using Math for Flexible Widths&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;!--
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://dandenney.com/dev/explanation.png&quot; alt=&quot;flexible math explanation&quot;&gt;
  --&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    So, now that I’m working with Compass and Sass one of the first things that I want to take advantage of is the math. One of my biggest pain points with responsive web design is using the calculator for the conversions to fluid widths. It bugged me so much that I learned a bunch of javascript to make a smoother way of doing
    &lt;a href='http://responsv.com/flexible-math'&gt;flexible math&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: I am new to writing mixins. There may be much, much better ways to do this. I am just sharing my learning. So, if you know of a better way please pop it in the comments.
    &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;span id='more-355'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;The Calculator is not my friend&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The entire goal of flexible math was to be able to take known widths and divide them fast without having to then move decimals and add percentage signs. Sass does that stuff for you without the need to leave your editor, which is the bees knees.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This isn’t fancy, I’m not trying to make a grid or anything. I just want to able to say my column is 320px wide in a 960px container.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;pre class='language-css'&gt;&lt;code&gt;@mixin flexible-width ($context, $target) {&amp;#x000A;  width: (($target / $context) * 100%);&amp;#x000A;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;What does that do?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, what this little mixin does is sets up “flexible-width”, which is made up of a context and a target. Then it divides them, leaving a decimal. Then it multiplies that decimal by 100%. (This took a little figuring out on where to put the ‘%’)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So now anytime I need a percentage width where I know the context and the target, all I have to do is call my mixin with the pixel widths:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;.boom-dan-does-sass-now {&amp;#x000A;  @include flexible-width (960, 320);&amp;#x000A;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The actual compiled CSS is:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;.boom-dan-does-sass-now {&amp;#x000A;  width: 33.333%;&amp;#x000A;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Boom!&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Now I won’t have to do any actual conversions and won’t even have to leave the CSS file to have flexible percentage widths. Thanks again to
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/parenteau'&gt;@parenteau&lt;/a&gt;
    for the nudge. I’ll be sharing my learnings as I go.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Accuracy
    &lt;strike&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strike&gt;
    Update
  &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    By default, the number was going to 3 decimal points. Sharing this post led the awesome
    &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/chriscoyier'&gt;Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt;
    to chime in on a solution for that. You just update your config.rb with this funky little stuff and set how deep you want the rabbit hole to go:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-markup'&gt;Sass::Script::Number.precision = 10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Also, there is a much better way to do the percentage. Sass actually has a built-in function called percentage so a mixin isn't necessary.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;.mo-better-percentage {&amp;#x000A;  width: percentage(320px / 960px);&amp;#x000A;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Sass and Compass Pairing with Michael Parenteau</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/sass-compass-pairing-with-michael-parenteau"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/front-end-dev/sass-compass-pairing-with-michael-parenteau</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://michaelparenteau.com'&gt;Michael Parenteau&lt;/a&gt;, aka
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/parenteau'&gt;@parenteau&lt;/a&gt;
  recently offered to show me the ropes of getting started with Sass and Compass on a project. He works for
  &lt;a href='http://thinkrelevance.com'&gt;Relevance&lt;/a&gt;
  and does some really fun side projects so I jumped at the chance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Prior to this, I have overanalyzed preprocessors. I've probably read 30 articles, glazed over at least that many repos of code and gotten a feel for which type my favorite people are using, if any. My only real experience was converting files to .scss so I could smoosh them with
  &lt;a href='http://incident57.com/codekit'&gt;Codekit&lt;/a&gt;
  I had decided to go with Sass with the SCSS syntax and to master it before jumping into Compass. Michael changed all that pretty quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I knew that my end goal was to get to Compass too, but I wanted to be sure I could write my own Sass mixins competently first. In this case, though, I think I'll learn more by using Compass and studying the
  &lt;a href='http://compass-style.org/reference/compass'&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt;
  to learn how to write solid mixins. Plus, there are just so many great design patterns in there.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One big win is the automated handling of vendor prefixes. As a disclaimer, I don't write vendor prefixes. I either copy and paste them from things like
  &lt;a href='http://css3please.com'&gt;CSS3Please.com&lt;/a&gt;
  or use
  &lt;a href='http://prefixr.com'&gt;Prefixr&lt;/a&gt;
  (I've recently had loads of trouble with Prefixr if I have the super cross-browser gradient CSS in my file, though.) So, Compass helps by writing all of the prefixes for me. I can just write something that makes sense to me and then it goes and gets all the stuff to make me a competent front-end dev.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Here is a really basic conversion of code that is just so much more friendly to write. This button code was from this repo:
  &lt;a href='https://github.com/ubuwaits/css3-buttons'&gt;CSS3 Buttons&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;button {&amp;#x000A;  background-color: #7fbf4d;&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-gradient(linear, left top, left bottom, from(#7fbf4d), to(#63a62f));&amp;#x000A;  /* Saf4+, Chrome */&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(top, #7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -moz-linear-gradient(top, #7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -ms-linear-gradient(top, #7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -o-linear-gradient(top, #7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: linear-gradient(top, #7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  border: 1px solid #63a62f;&amp;#x000A;  border-bottom: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -ms-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -o-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  -ms-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  -o-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  color: #fff;&amp;#x000A;  float: right;&amp;#x000A;  font-size: 1.5em;&amp;#x000A;  line-height: 1;&amp;#x000A;  padding: .75em 0 .8em 0;&amp;#x000A;  text-align: center;&amp;#x000A;  text-shadow: 0 -1px 0 #4c9021;&amp;#x000A;  width: 150px; }&amp;#x000A;  &amp;#x000A;button.more_info {&amp;#x000A;  font-size: 1em;&amp;#x000A;  padding: .25em 0 .4em 0; }&amp;#x000A;&amp;#x000A; button:hover {&amp;#x000A;    background-color: #76b347;&amp;#x000A;    background-image: -webkit-gradient(linear, left top, left bottom, from(#76b347), to(#5e9e2e));&amp;#x000A;    /* Saf4+, Chrome */&amp;#x000A;    background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(top, #76b347, #5e9e2e);&amp;#x000A;    background-image: -moz-linear-gradient(top, #76b347, #5e9e2e);&amp;#x000A;    background-image: -ms-linear-gradient(top, #76b347, #5e9e2e);&amp;#x000A;    background-image: -o-linear-gradient(top, #76b347, #5e9e2e);&amp;#x000A;    background-image: linear-gradient(top, #76b347, #5e9e2e);&amp;#x000A;    -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;    -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;    -ms-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;    -o-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;    box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;    cursor: pointer; }&amp;#x000A;&amp;#x000A;button:active {&amp;#x000A;    border: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;    border-bottom: 1px solid #538c27;&amp;#x000A;    -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;    -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;    -ms-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;    -o-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;    box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee; }&amp;#x000A;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a whole lotta CSS, huh? Think I'm ever going back in there to pull those vendor prefixes once they're approved? Not likely. However, Compass stays on top of them so if I ever recompile the file it will irradicate unnecessary ones for me. Again, making me better than I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we did some extra stuff to the new version of the button but here is the new code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;button {&amp;#x000A;  @include button(#7fbf4d, #63a62f, 3px, 1px solid #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  @include box-shadow(inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d);&amp;#x000A;  border-bottom: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;  color: #fff;&amp;#x000A;  float: right;&amp;#x000A;  font-size: 1.5em;&amp;#x000A;  line-height: 1;&amp;#x000A;  padding: .75em 0 .8em 0;&amp;#x000A;  text-shadow: 0 -1px 0 #4c9021;&amp;#x000A;  width: 150px;&amp;#x000A;  &amp;:hover {&amp;#x000A;    @include box-shadow(inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67);&amp;#x000A;  }&amp;#x000A;  &amp;:active {&amp;#x000A;    @include box-shadow(inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee);&amp;#x000A;    border: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;      border-bottom: 1px solid #538c27;&amp;#x000A;  } &amp;#x000A;}&amp;#x000A;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is that more concise, it is waaaay more powerful and extendable. We made our own button mixin that sets the things that will be on every button to be written right away. I won't go into the full breakdown here but this is the kind of code that I want to be writing. Lean and mean, man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Compass writes all of the boring stuff for me and this is the end result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='language-css'&gt;button {&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-gradient(linear, 50% 0%, 50% 100%, color-stop(0%, #7fbf4d), color-stop(100%, #63a62f));&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(#7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -moz-linear-gradient(#7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -o-linear-gradient(#7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -ms-linear-gradient(#7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: linear-gradient(#7fbf4d, #63a62f);&amp;#x000A;  *zoom: 1;&amp;#x000A;  filter: progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.gradient(gradientType=0, startColorstr='#FF7FBF4D', endColorstr='#FF63A62F');&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -ms-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  -o-border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  border-radius: 3px;&amp;#x000A;  border: 1px solid #63a62f;&amp;#x000A;  text-align: center;&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #96ca6d;&amp;#x000A;  border-bottom: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;  color: #fff;&amp;#x000A;  float: right;&amp;#x000A;  font-size: 1.5em;&amp;#x000A;  line-height: 1;&amp;#x000A;  padding: .75em 0 .8em 0;&amp;#x000A;  text-shadow: 0 -1px 0 #4c9021;&amp;#x000A;  width: 150px;&amp;#x000A;}&amp;#x000A;button:hover {&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-gradient(linear, 50% 0%, 50% 100%, color-stop(0%, #72b240), color-stop(100%, #61a22e));&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(#72b240, #61a22e);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -moz-linear-gradient(#72b240, #61a22e);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -o-linear-gradient(#72b240, #61a22e);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: -ms-linear-gradient(#72b240, #61a22e);&amp;#x000A;  background-image: linear-gradient(#72b240, #61a22e);&amp;#x000A;  *zoom: 1;&amp;#x000A;  filter: progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.gradient(gradientType=0, startColorstr='#FF72B240', endColorstr='#FF61A22E');&amp;#x000A;  cursor: pointer;&amp;#x000A;}&amp;#x000A;button:hover {&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;  box-shadow: inset 0 1px 0 0 #8dbf67;&amp;#x000A;}&amp;#x000A;button:active {&amp;#x000A;  -webkit-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;  -moz-box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;  box-shadow: inset 0 0 8px 4px #548c29, 0 1px 0 0 #eeeeee;&amp;#x000A;  border: 1px solid #5b992b;&amp;#x000A;  border-bottom: 1px solid #538c27;&amp;#x000A;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I want to give a huge thank you to Michael. We paired for a little over 2 hours but he also showed me a ton and gave me a breakdown of Ribbons. Plus, showed off a rad deploy script he set up. He gave me the nudge I needed to really dive into this stuff and learn it. I'm going to be a much better developer for it, too. If you want a nudge, he really digs sharing so you might want to
  &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/parenteau'&gt;@ him on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
  and see if he'd like to pair with you when he has some time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Rebuilding</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/general/rebuilding"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/general/rebuilding</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm in the process of rebuilding my personal site. It kinda sucks that I was more or less forced into it, but I have wanted to do it for a while. I'm taking it as an opportunity to do something very different.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CMS Free&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It sounds crazy but I am not going to use any CMS on this site. I have been writing markup for about 11 years and the past 2 have been primarily in a Rails environment. Aside from that, I have some WordPress and ExpressionEngine experience. In all of these, you have to deal with a great deal of markup that isn't of your choosing. Things come in dynamically from the framework, gems, plugins, etc. Inspired by
  &lt;a href='http://www.zeldman.com/2012/05/18/web-design-manifesto-2012'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Zeldman's recent post
  , I'm going back to my personal site being my playground and I want to choose all of the sand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't recommend this to everyone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a personal preference and exploration and it is horribly inefficient for business purposes. However, working on my personal site is a hobby. It is a time for playing and for relaxation. I don't relax when I am pasting code into a WordPress input and reading about how to not have it wrap my sample &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; tags in a &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; tag. I debated on a static site generator but they have a weird feel about them too. Most want to lean towards markdown and have a long list of helpers to learn. For work and efficency these are very good things but I love markup and I want to write it. I just want to write it and I want every piece of markup in this site to be a conscious choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building in Public&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don't get a lot of traffic, but those of you who made it here will get to see this process and I'll share how things go. Here are my to-dos:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Build a list of all the things that I use to rebuild. (ongoing)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15&quot; Macbook Pro&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Codekit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mediatemple Hosting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Typekit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Muji Notebook&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some random pen&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Icomoon&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;xScope&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kuler&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;0to255&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;
      Set up Github, both for versioning and to deploy to the server.
    &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;
      Gather the resources that I know I'll need for design (fonts and images).
    &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;
      Define how to structure the files.
    &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;
      Design the nav.
    &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strike&gt;
      Design the basic post style.
    &lt;/strike&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Get recent posts back up in the basic post style. (The ones below have content but you'll need your back button)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href='/posts/front-end-dev/sass-compass-pairing-with-michael-parenteau'&gt;Sass and Compass Pairing with Michael Parenteau&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href='/posts/front-end-dev/a-sass-noob-using-math-for-flexible-widths'&gt;A Sass Noob Using Math for Flexible Widths&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  That will get me started and I'll have a MVW (minimum viable website). Getting the recent posts back up are important to me because I had shared how much a few people had helped me recently and I want those back up so others know how awesome they are.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you, kinda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it sucks that some script kiddies started injecting my database with malware, it has gotten me passionate about rebuilding my personal site. So thank you, kinda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='post-standard-signature'&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
    June 16, 2012
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Fluid</title>
 		<link href="http://dandenney.com/posts/general/fluid"/>
 		<updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>http://dandenney.com/posts/general/fluid</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm an unapologetic fan of responsive web design. However, it's not necessarily the technique itself that has won me over. It is what it has done to the way I look at the web and the way I look at my role in building things for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing responsive designs for the first time gave form to something that had always sat wrong with me in web design. At it's very nature, content put on the web is fluid. If you start a basic HTML document with text, that text will adapt to fill the alotted space. For years, we decided to put our own canvas in there. It never sat right with me but it took someone else describing it for me to put my finger on it. Thank you, Ethan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, there have been some other folks that have said wonderful things that define my feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &quot;My love for responsive centers around the idea that my website will meet you wherever you are—from mobile to full-blown desktop and anywhere in between.&quot;
  &lt;cite&gt;
    Trent Walton
    &lt;a href='http://trentwalton.com/2011/05/10/fit-to-scale'&gt;Fit to Scale&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &quot;We know very little about a visitor to our website. We actually know less and less every day, as the demographics of internet users widens (younger and older, no longer a nerd thing, more areas geographically, etc.) So as we march forward toward the next 6 billion people using the web, let's embrace the unknown by accommodating for it.&quot;
  &lt;cite&gt;
    Chris Coyier
    &lt;a href='http://css-tricks.com/what-we-dont-know/'&gt;What We Don't Know&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &quot;So a responsive design doesn't mean you have to be entirely fluid. It just means it is &quot;responding&quot; to it's environment, and how you do this will be different based on the challenges of individual projects, the elements therein, and under what circumstances they are being viewed and interacted with.&quot;
  &lt;cite&gt;
    Kev Adamson
    &lt;a href='http://www.kevadamson.com/talking-of-design/article/how-i-am-skinning-my-resposive-cat'&gt;How I Am Skinning My Responsive Cat&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first two nail my thoughts about what the web should be. The third one, though, speaks more to what I think my role should be. Responsive web design isn't about resizing your browser, it's about embracing the medium and using technology to enhance the experience. It's about embracing the fluidity of web design practices the challenges of projects. It's vital to know and embrace that how I code something this week is different than 3 months ago and will be even more different in 3 months. For my sanity, it's important to remember that sometimes the waves will be going with me and sometimes they will be rolling against me. The most important part is not to make my own constraints, not get tied to specific code or methodoligies. Everything is changing and changing fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;March 12, 2012&lt;/small&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 

</feed>